Annus A. Siddiqui

18W237 Knollwood Lane Villa Park, IL 60181 (630) 525-0908 annusasiddiqui@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Bachelor's in the Science of Nursing holder from Purdue University with a strong academic background in nursing combined with over five years of supervisory and medical experience in nursing health care, ranging from both acute to sub-acute clinical environments. I am BLS, ACLS, and NIHSS certified, as well as proficient with a variety of nursing specialties. Regarded as focused and avid learner with a responsible work ethic, which would be well suited for many different professional opportunities.

LICENSURE & CERTIFICATIONS

Illinois State RN License: August 2014 - May 31, 2018 Illinois State LPN License: January 2012 - January 31, 2015 ACLS - Advanced Cardiac Life Support: November 2014 - 2017

BLS for Healthcare Providers: November 2014 - 2017

NIH Stroke Scale Training and Certification: November 2014

EDUCATION

Purdue University

B.S.N.. – Bachelor's of Science in Nursing – September 2016

College of DuPage

A.D.N. - Associates Degree in Nursing - May 2014 Certificate in Practical Nursing - December 2011

Samland Institute of Allied Health and Technology

CNA Training Program and Certification - Fall 2007

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fresenius Medical Care NA, Elmhurst, IL

Acute RN/Staff Nurse, September 2015 - Current

Lakewood Nursing and Rehabilitation Center, Plainfield, IL

Staff Nurse/Nursing Supervisor, February 2015 – September 2015

Courtyard Healthcare Center, Berwyn, IL

Staff Nurse/Nursing Supervisor, February 2012 - September 2014

CLINICAL RESPONSIBILITIES

Fresenius Medical Care NA

- Provided prescribed hemodialysis treatment to patients suffering from acute renal injury or end stage renal disease in both the acute hospital setting as well as the chronic clinic setting.
- Provided hemodialysis in acute care settings such as intensive care units, cardiac telemetry units, medical-surgical units, oncology units, and psychiatric units.
- Monitored patient's response to dialysis treatments and changes the plan as ordered by the MD.
- Oversaw hemodialysis technicians in initiation, during, and termination of hemodialysis treatment.

- Administers medications and blood products prescribed by MD in regards anemia, protein, and bone and mineral management.
- Arbitrated problems arising from treatment parameters both medical and psychosocial
- Performed patient assessment pre and post treatment.
- Initiated and followed up with proper referrals in regards to access issues to MD, vascular surgeon, social worker, dietitian, or clinic manager.

<u>Lakewood Nursing and Rehabilitation Center/Courtyard Healthcare Center</u>

- Provided direct patient care, medication administration, treatments, dressing changes, monitoring electrolytes and labs, and equipment maintenance for a variety of acutely ill patients
- Provided skilled nursing care for patients with complex multi-system disorders ranging from end stage renal disease, including patients on peritoneal dialysis and hemodialysis; cardiovascular disease, including patients with atrial fibrillation, uncontrolled hypertension, and congestive heart failure; cognitive and mental health disorders, including patients with schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, schizoaffective disorder, major depressive disorder; and other chronic medical conditions, including Parkinson's disease, Alzheimer's disease, and dementia
- Made skilled nursing decisions and communicated with physicians regarding observed changes in patient status or condition, ongoing patient needs, abnormal lab values, necessary medications reconciliations or adjustments
- Intervened in emergency situations by way of rapid response and notifying proper authorities such as physicians, hospitals, and EMT personnel
- Educated patients and families in medications and home/discharge care
- Collaborated with an interdisciplinary team to bring about the best outcomes for patients, including physicians, dietary/nutritional services, physical and occupational therapy, social services, case management, and MDS care plan coordinators